Muhammad Abubakar

🗷 (+44) 7778926477 | 💌 abubakarx72@gmail.com | 🛅 Muhammad Abubakar | 🗘 abubakar20-02 | ♥ London

Profile

I am an enthusiastic computer science graduate who loves to solve challenging problems by using an efficient approach. I have 3 years in python software development, building back end and front end using python. I am excited by conversations in software architecture and cloud technology.

EDUCATION

University of Nottingham

Nottingham, Nottinghamshire

Sep 2020 - May 2023

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science with Artificial Intelligence
• Awarded Second Upper (2:1)

Work Experience

Software Developer Internship

Jun 2022 – Aug 2022

Zeenat Jewellers

Manama, Kingdom of Bahrain

- Developed a windows desktop application to add logo to images in batches as per client's business requirement
- Isolated GUI elements from the business logic by incorporating an end to end multi-threaded architecture
- Provided a finished product shipped with a setup file, reducing the manual processes by harnessing automation

Additional Experience

Sales Assistant

Oct 2023 - Present

Hamleys St. Pancras International Station

London, United Kingdom

- Working as a team of 2-6 to manage the store providing assistance to customers, maintaining store shelves and ensuring that the store is in perfect condition
- · Responsible for managing the tills and checkout, processing transactions both in cash and credit cards
- Achieved a flawless 100% performance rating during the peak Christmas period by providing excellent customer service

Projects

Cover Letter Generator | AWS. Google Cloud Platform (OAuth), React, JavaScript

Jul 2023 - Present

- Building a cover letter generator utilizing open AI's capabilities to generate tailored cover letters
- Utilizing a secured RESTful Web API linking the back end logic with the front end
- Implementing an Oauth flow capable of adding multiple Google accounts as a medium of authenticating a user

GoldFolio | Python, PyQt5, MySQL, Matplotlib, Machine Learning

Sep 2022 – May 2023

- $\bullet \ \ \text{Developed an advanced Python desktop app using PyQt5 framework for gold investment management with simple analysis}$
- $\bullet \ \ {\rm Designed} \ \ {\rm and} \ \ {\rm developed} \ \ {\rm away} \ \ {\rm to} \ \ {\rm undo} \ \ {\rm destructive} \ \ {\rm changes} \ \ {\rm such} \ \ {\rm as} \ \ {\rm delete} \ \ {\rm by} \ \ {\rm using} \ \ {\rm data} \ \ {\rm archives} \ \ {\rm and} \ \ {\rm logging} \ \ {\rm databases}$
- Incorporated an advanced predictive analysis of future gold prices using machine learning, for informed decision making

 ${\bf HeatGen} \mid Python, \ PyQt5, \ Numpy, \ Pandas, \ Matplotlib, \ Multi-Threading, \ Deep \ learning, \ Github$

Sep 2021 – May 2022

- Engineered a neural network-based application to generate heat-map of bricks using a set of 1D variables
- Managed a team of 4 to develop the front end of the application and I was responsible for making sure both the front end and back end remained compatible throughout the development cycle
- Designed and developed a multi-threaded architecture to disconnect the user interface with the back end logic
- Published journal in JESTEC, Volume 18. Issue 2

Android Fitness Tracker | Android Studio, Google Map SDK, OOP, SQLite, MVVM

Dec 2022 – Jan 2023

- Constructed an android application capable of measuring a user's running data and displaying previous run's data with the ability to annotate it
- Utilized google map's SDK to display user's path and store it's information in the database
- Designed and implemented a solution that allows user to switch to different application while fitness tracker is running in the background

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Python, Java, Java(Android Studio), JavaScript, HTML/CSS

Frameworks: Flask, PyQt5, React Libraries: Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib

Developer Tools and Technologies: Git, GitHub, Docker, Postman, Amazon Web Services (AWS), Google Cloud Platform (OAuth), RESTful API (Web API), JSON

 $\textbf{Industry Knowledge}: \ \ \text{Object Oriented Programming (OOP)} \ , \ \ \text{Multi-Threading, Software Maintenance, Software Testing} \ .$

Databases: MySQL, Firebase, DynamoDB(AWS)